Stephen E. Malawista papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Talks and Travel ("T/T"), Series IX
  - 1990s
    - 37th Annual Meeting of the Japan Rheumatism Association, Nagoya, Japan, 1993 May 22 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      Malawista's presentation was "Lyme Disease: Current Problems in Diagnosis, Therapy, and Prevention."
    - Sixth Annual Rheumatology Symposium - Lyme Disease, Yale University, 1993 June 16 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Gordon Conference on Phagocytes, Plymouth, New Hampshire, 1993 July 4-9 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - "Lyme Disease" Grand Rounds, Middlesex Hospital, 1993 July 22 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Malawista presented on Lyme disease.
    - Grokoest Prize Program, New York, 1993 August 4 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      The Arthritis Foundation, New York Chapter, selected student summer fellowships in rheumatic and musculoskeletal diseases for the Albert W. Grokoest Prize. Grokoest, who had died in 1991, was a faculty member of Columbia University, College of Physicians and Surgeons for over 40 years. Malawista's talk was "Remembrance of a Mentor." Text of talk not in folder.
    - Shenson Visiting Professor of Clinical Medicine, Stanford University, 1993 September 20-24 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      Malawista's presentation was "Lyme Disease: Soup to Nuts."
    - Paul Klemperer Presentation, New York Academy of Medicine, 1993 October 26 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      Malawista was a member of the Award Committee
    - Interurban Clinical Club, 1993 November 5-6 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - American College of Rheumatology Annual Meeting, San Antonio, 1993 November 7-11 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - "Lyme Disease," SUNY Brooklyn, 1994 February 22 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Harvard-MIT External Advisory Committee, 1994 March 16 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Interurban Clinical Club, Philadelphia, 1994 April 8-9 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Misoprostol Research Symposium (Searle), Chicago, 1994 April 14-15 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      See Series 5, Grant and Contract Proposals, Contracts.
    - Clinical Research Meeting, Phagocyte Workshop, Baltimore, 1994 April 28-29 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Harvard College 40th Reunion, Newport, R.I., 1994 June 9 (Box 66, Folder 15)
      Folder includes Malawista's class biography for the 30th and 35th reunions
    - 6th International Congress on Lyme Borreliosis, Bologna, Italy, 1994 June 19-22 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - American College of Rheumatology Annual Meeting, Minneapolis, 1994 October 23-27 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Malawista was on sabbatical in Paris. It is not clear that he attended this meeting,
    - XI Pan American Congress of Rheumatology, Recife, Brazil, 1994 September 18-23 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - American College of Rheumatology, "Meet the Professor," San Francisco, 1995 October 23-26 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Malawista participated in two sessions of "Meet the Professor" on the subject of Lyme Disease. Folder also includes materials on the Nominating Committee on which Malawista was serving.
    - First Annual Infectious Disease Symposium: Tick-Borne Diseases, Foxwoods, Ledyard, Conn., 1995 October 27-28 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Malawista presented "Lyme Disease: Epidemiology and Clinical Manifestations."
    - Interurban Clinical Club, Boston, 1995 November 3 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Symposium on Challenges in Infectious Diseases, Zurich, 1996 April 11 (Box 67, Folder 6)
      Malawista presented "Lyme Disease/Ehrlichiosis."
    - Charles W. Thomas Lecture, Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, 1996 May 2 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Malawista presented "Lyme Disease: Infectious in Origin, Rheumatic in Expression."
    - 18th Annual Phagocyte Workshop, Washington, D.C., 1996 May 3 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Ninth Yale University Lyme Disease Symposium, New Haven, 1996 May 26 (Box 67, Folder 9)
      Malawista presented "PCR: Uses and Pitfalls."
    - 28th Scandinavian Congress of Rheumatology, Reykjavik, Iceland, 1996 May 31 - June 3 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - VII International Congress on Lyme Borreliosis, San Francisco, 1996 June 16-21 (Box 67, Folder 11)
      Malawista served as a committee member reviewing abstracts for the VII International Congress on Lyme Borreliosis.
    - Gordon Conference, Plymouth, New Hampshire, 1996 June 23-28 (Box 67, Folder 12)
      Malawista presented "Chemotactic Cytokines."
    - Boland Lecture, Mayo Clinic, 1996 August 7 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      Malawista presented the Edward W. Boland lecture in Rheumatology, "Lyme Disease: Infectious in Origin, Rheumatic in Expression." File includes a picture of Malawista.
    - Interurban Clinical Club, New Haven, 1996 October 8 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Paul Klemperer Award, New York Academy of Medicine, 1996 October 8 (Box 67, Folder 15)
      Folder cntains Malawista's correspondence with John Atkinson, ninth Paul Klemperer Medalist, who gave a the lecture, "Regulation of a powerful recognition and effector system of immunity and inflammation: The example of the complement system."
    - "Meet the Professor" session, American College of Rheumatology, Orlando, Florida, 1996 October 18-22 (Box 67, Folder 16)
      Malawista presented two sessions on Lyme disease for "Meet the Professor."
    - Interurban Clinical Club, Philadelphia, 1996 November 1 (Box 67, Folder 17)
      Presented "Lyme Disease Infectious in Origin, Rheumatic in Expression".
    - Grand Rounds, St. Vincent's Hospital, New York, 1996 November 8 (Box 67, Folder 18)
      Presented "Lyme Disease Infectious in Origin, Rheumatic in Expression."
    - NIAMS Review Committee, 1996 November 11 (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Interurban Clinical Club, New York, 1997 April 4 (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Phagocyte Workshop, Washington, D.C., 1997 April 25 (Box 67, Folder 21)
    - Interplanetary Society, Port Ludlow, Washington, 1997 May 30-June 2 (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Gordon Conference on Phagocytes, Plymouth, New Hampshire, 1997 June 8-13 (Box 67, Folder 23)
    - Paul Klemperer Award, New York Academy of Medicine, 1997 October 14 (Box 67, Folder 24)
      Gerald Weissmann was the awardee at the Tenth Paul Klemperer Award and Lecture, New York Academy of Medicine.
    - Visiting Committee for Whitaker College, MIT, 1997 October 28-30 (Box 67, Folder 25)
    - "Meet the Professor' sessions, American College of Rheumatology, Washington, D.C., 1997 November 9 (Box 67, Folder 26)
      Evaluation summary for Malawista's sessions on Lyme disease for "Meet the Professor" at the American College of Rheumatology Annual meeting.
    - Immunologie Cellulaire & Moleculaire, Paris, 1997 November 28 (Box 67, Folder 27)
      Presentation: "Fonction motile des polynucleaires et de leurs cytoplasts."
    - American Society of Hematology, San Diego, 1997 December 5-9 (Box 67, Folder 28)
      Malawista may not have attended.
    - Medical Grand Rounds, New York University, 1998 March 11 (Box 67, Folder 29)
      Presents "Lyme disease: From Soup to Nuts."
    - Interurban Clinical Club, Boston, 1998 April 3 (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Harvard Crimson, 125th Anniversary, 1998 May 8-10 (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - Gordon Research Conference, Motile and Contractile Systems, New London, New Hampshire, 1998 June 7-12 (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Granulocytes for Transfusion, Bethesda, Maryland, 1998 September 11 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - American College of Rheumatology, San Diego, 1998 November (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Slides for a presentation on gout, 1998 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Patient-Oriented Research, First Annual Meeting, 1999 April 30-May 2 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Presented "Chronic Lyme arthritis: Lessons from a single patient, and then from several."
    - Paul Klemperer Award presentation, New York, 1998 November 2 (Box 68, Folder 5)
      The awardee/speaker was Dr. Stuart Schlossman.
    - AOA Lecture, NYU, 1999 May 3 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Gordon Research Conference, New London, Conn., 1999 June 6-11 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - VIII International Conference on Lyme Borreliosis, Munich, 1999 June 20-24 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Interurban Clinical Club, New York, 1999 November 5 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - 12th Paul Klemperer Award & Lecture, New York, 1999 November 8 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      It is not clear that Malawista attended.
    - American College of Rheumatology, Boston, 1999 November 12-17 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Malawista was named a Master of the American College of Rheumatology.
    - Visiting Committee, Whitaker College, MIT, Boston, 1999 November 15-16 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - 2000s
    - Biotechnology Study Center, NYU, 2000 April 4 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Yale University School of Medicine, Rheumatology Symposium, 2000 April 5 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      The symposium, "Current Issues in Rheumatolgy," offered CME credits that Malawista received. He was not a speaker.
    - Interurban Clinical Club, New Haven, 2000 April 7 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - American College of Rheumatology, Philadelphia, 2000 October 28-November 2 (Box 68, Folder 16)
      Presented on Lyme Disease in "Practice and Therapy" Panel.
    - Seminar in Advanced Rheumatology, NYU School of Medicine, 2001 March 1-4 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Clinical Research/ Association for Patient-Oriented Research, Arlington, Virginia, 2001 March 8-11 (Box 68, Folder 18)
      Presented "Lyme Arthritis: A New Look."
    - Rheumatology Symposium, Westchester Medical Group, White Plains, New York, 2001 May 9 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Gordon Conference, Phagocytes, New London, Conn., 2001 June 10-15 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Interplanetary Society Meeting, Seattle, 2001 June 22-24 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - International Conference on Lyme Borreliosis, Brussels, Belgium, 2001 November 16 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - IX International Conference on Lyme Borreliosis, New York, 2002 August 18-22 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence with Gary Wormser and Diane Mathis on Lyme disease.
    - Paul Klemperer Lecture, New York Academy of Medicine, 2002 October 16 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      Malawista was the awardee/speaker. His presentation was "Tell Me What You See..."
    - American College of Rheumatology, New Orleans, 2002 October 24-29 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Southern New England Fall Rheumatology Lecture and Dinner, New Haven, 2002 November 14 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Interurban Clinical Club, Boston, 2003 April 4 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Danbury Hospital Research Day, Danbury, Conn., 2003 May 7 (Box 69, Folder 10)
      Gave talk, "Understanding the Curious Clinical Facts of Lyme Disease."
    - American College of Rheumatology, Winter Rheumatology Symposium, Snowmass, Colorado, 2003 January 25-31 (Box 69, Folder 11)
      Gave talks, "A New Look at the Curious Clinical Facts of Lyme Arthritis" and "How to Eat a Spirochete."
    - Gordon Research, Phagocytes, New London, Conn., 2003 June 8-12 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Microtubule Symposium, Woods Hole, Mass., 2003 August 1-2 (Box 69, Folder 13)
      Gave talk, "Ancient History: Getting at Microtubules."
    - Society for Leukocyte Biology, Philadelphia, 2003 October 2-5 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - American College of Rheumatology, Orlando, 2003 October 24-28 (Box 69, Folder 15)
      Malawista received the 2003 ACR Presidential Gold Medal.
    - Symposium in honor of Steven E. Malawista, MD, Yale University School of Medicine, 2004 April 23 (Box 69, Folder 16)
      Malawista presented, "Reflections on Neutrophils, Inflammation, and Lyme Disease." There were seven other speakers, followed by a reception, a concert, and a dinner. See also Box 1.
    - American College of Rheumatology, San Antonio, 2004 October 16-21 (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Gordon Conference, Phagocytes, New London, Conn., 2005 June 12-17 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - American College of Rheumatology, San Diego, 2005 November 13-17 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Immune Function and Biodefense in Children, Elderly and Immunocompromised Populations, Washington, D.C., 2006 September 27-28 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      Annual Meeting sponsored by NIAID, NIH. Erol Fikrig, Malawista's colleague, spoke on "Innate Immune Response in Elderly and Immunosuppressed."
    - American College of Rheumatology, Washington, D.C., 2006 November 10-15 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Gordon Conference, Phagocytes, Smithfield, Rhode Island, 2007 June 10-15 (Box 70, Folder 5)
      Includes photo of attendees.
    - American College of Rheumatology, Boston, 2007 November 6-11 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Immune Function and Biodefense in Children, Elderly, and Immunocompromised Populations, Seattle, 2008 October 6-7 (Box 70, Folder 7)
      This meeting, organized by the Division of Allergy, Immunology and Transplantation, NIAID, NIH, was for the presentation of progress reports on contracts awarded under the topic, "Immune Function and Biodefense in Children, Elderly, and Immunosuppressed Populations." Ruth Montgomery was on the program presenting for the Yale group. Folder contains copies of a PowerPoint presentation by Malawista, "IMAGIN project: Progress in Studies of Immunosuppressed Subjects."
    - 11th International Conference on Lyme Borreliosis and Other Tick-Borne Diseases, Irvine, California, 2008 October 19-22 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - American College of Rheumatology, San Francisco, 2008 October 25-29 (Box 70, Folder 9)
      Concert at which Tobe Malawista sang. Also "Plotz/Malawista in Concert" singing "Fugue for Detail Men."
    - Immune Function and Biodefense in Children, Elderly, and Immunocompromised Populations, Philadelphia, 2009 September 24-25 (Box 70, Folder 10)
      This meeting was organized by the Division of Allergy, Immunology and Transplantation of NIAID/NIH. The Yale faculty working under the contract gave the presentation, "IMAGIN project: IMmunosuppressed AGing INnate immunity." Ruth Montgomery and Erol Fikrig were Co-PIs. Malawista was a member of the team.
    - American College of Rheumatology, Philadelphia, 2009 October 17-21 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - 2010s
    - 12th International Conference on Lyme Borreliosis and Other Tick-Borne Diseases, Ljubljana, Slovenia, 2010 September 26-29 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - American College of Rheumatology, Atlanta, 2010 November 7-11 (Box 70, Folder 13)
- Published articles (reprints), Series X
  When he published an article, Malawista purchased as many as 400 printed copies (reprints) of it. Reprints could often be ordered with covers or without. Malawista ordered some of each. He sent reprints in response to postcard requests, included selected reprints in grants, and brought relevant reprints to talks and meetings to give to those who were interested. Later in his career, when journals began to be published online, printed reprints were no longer as available. By 2010 the culture of trading reprints had largely ended. Reprints were found scattered in Malawista's collection. They are here organized by year and include both peer-reviewed articles and "reviews" (see CV in Box 1, Folder 1, and attached to finding aid). Reprints that Malawista received from others have not been kept except for those on Lyme disease.
  - Articles, 1962-1964 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1965 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1966-1967 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1974 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1975 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Articles, 1976 (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Articles, 1977 (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Articles, 1978 (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1979 (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Articles, 1980 (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Articles, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 17)
  - Articles, 1982 (Box 71, Folder 18)
  - Articles, 1983 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Articles, 1984 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1985 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1986 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1988 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1991 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1993 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1994 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Articles, 1995 (Box 72, Folder 12)
  - Articles, 1996 (Box 72, Folder 13)
  - Articles, 1997 (Box 72, Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1998 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Articles, 1999 (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Articles, 2000 (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Articles, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Articles, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Articles, 2003-2008 (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Articles, no date (Box 72, Folder 21)
- Research materials, Series XI
  - Research protocols and procedures, Subseries 1
    These protocols for research were identified by number and approved annually by the Yale University Human Investigation Committee. Protocols typically do not contain patient names, although the Lyme disease protocols in Series 8, Lyme Vaccine Study, do have reports on adverse reactions identified by study participant.
    - Protocol for a clinical trial of anti-metabolite therapy, 1967-1968 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      The trial was to test anti-metabolite therapy in patients with SLE nephritis. The drug to be tested as an immunosuppressive was Azathioprine ("Imuran").
    - Protocol 1018: "Phagocytosis and Bacterial Killing in Renal Transplant Tubules," Mary Jean Ahern, P.I., 1975 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Mary Jean Ahern was a 2nd year fellow in the Infectious Disease Section of Internal Medicine. Malawista and Vincent Andriole were other investigators for this project.
    - Animal protocol 2000, 1975-1980, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      This folder contains mainly communications from Albert V. Jonas, D.V.M., Director of the Division of Animal Care at Yale, and also Guide for the Care and Use of Laboratory Animals, NIH,1972.
    - Protocol 1125: "Evaluation of Epidemic Lyme Arthritis in the Lyme, Connecticut Area," Allen C. Steere, P.I., 1975-1984 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Malawista was among the other investigators for this study. A later title for the study was "Lyme Arthritis: A New Epidemic." There is one patient record by name at the end of the folder.
    - Draft protocol: "Treatment of Glucocorticoid Induced Osteoporosis," Howard Rasmussen, P.I., 1976 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Malawista was an investigator on this protocol. The protocol is not signed or numbered.
    - Protocol 5227: "Pathogenesis of Lyme Disease: Molecular Probes", 1989-1994 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      This protocol relates to a grant of the same title.
    - Protocol 5227: "Pathogenesis of Lyme Disease: Molecular Probes", 1995-2001 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Draft Protocol: "An Evaluation of an Immunogenetic Basis for Refractory Lyme Arthritis," Robert T. Schoen, P.I., 1996-1997 (Box 73, Folder 8)
      The study would attempt to identify a genetic risk factor for chronic Lyme arthritis. Malawista appears to have been an investigator in this study. The protocol was not yet signed or given a number.
    - Protocol 07459: "Biophysical Mechanisms in Leukocytes and Melanocytes,", 1997-2003 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      This was the animal research protocol for Malawista's main NIH grant. It was resubmitted each year to the Yale Animal Care and Use Committee.
    - Protocol 12468: "Colchicine and Theophylline in Asthma, Geoffrey Chupp, P.I., 2001 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      Malawista was an investigator in this clinical study.
    - "Standard procedures", ca. 1968-1970 (Box 73, Folder 11)
      The contents of this folder were removed from a three-ring binder.
    - "Procedures", 1973 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous procedures, 1991-2004 and no date (Box 73, Folder 13)
      Brief laboratory procedures including one on cryopreserved cytokineplasts.
    - "Stock Solutions" and miscellany, 1985-1987 (Box 73, Folder 14)
      The contents of this folder were removed from a three-ring binder labeled "Stock Solutions." Other materials were found inserted into the notebook. There are a few names of "donors."
  - Laboratory notebooks and binders (Restricted), Subseries 2
    These are notebooks kept in Malawista's laboratory. Most of the notebooks, except for those titled "Frog Skins," contain tests on fluids or tissues of named patients or donors. Malawista's staff often volunteered blood or other fluids for testing. The bulk of laboratory notes were entered in blank books, often purchased from the Yale Co-Operative Corporation. Other laboratory notes, overlapping in time, were maintained in three-ring binders.
    - Notebooks begun 1962-1970
      - J.W. Hollingsworth, Tests of joint fluids of patients, 1962-1966 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - S.E. Malawista, Loose graphs and notebook, 1963 December-1966 June (Box 74, Folder 2)
        Loose graphs from 1963-1964 were inserted in the notebook. The notebook contains only a few charts and graphs from June 1966.
      - Notebook, 1964 July-1965 October (Box 74, Folder 3)
        Notebook begins with a note from Malawista to "Phyllis" [Bodel] with directions.
      - Course on Physiology, Woods Hole, Massachusetts, 1965 June-July (Box 74, Folder 4)
        Malawista's course notes.
      - Course on Physiology, Woods Hole (continued), 1965 July (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - Woods Hole, 1966 April-1966 August (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - S.E. Malawista, "Colchicine and Phagocytosis," etc., 1966 April-December (Box 74, Folder 7)
        In Malawista's handwriting.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. I, 1966-1967 (Box 74, Folder 8)
        This is the first of a sequence of notebooks numbered by Malawista, though often the notebooks were not in his hand. Those begun through 1970 are being kept together in this arrangement by the archivist. See the next section for numbered notebooks begun 1971 to 1975. Volume I was begun by John R. Hill.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. II, Frog Skins, Book 1, 1966 October-1970 November (Box 74, Folder 9)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. III, Enzymes, 1967 January-1974 April (Box 74, Folder 10)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. IV, "Phage," Book 1, 1967 March-1970 March (Box 74, Folder 11)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. V, Studies of members of a family, Book I, 1967 April-1969 May (Box 74, Folder 12)
        Tests on sera, white blood counts, and bacteria, from members of a named family. See also Vol. XI for the same family.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. VI, "CO2, Phag[ocytosis], Warburg", 1967 April-1968 July (Box 74, Folder 13)
        Tests looking at CO2 production in white blood cells.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. VII, "Girls", 1968 January-1970 January (Box 74, Folder 14)
        About hormones in women. Continued in Volume IX.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. VIII, General, 1968 October-1970 March (Box 74, Folder 15)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. IX, Lactate general - Girls Cont., 1968 August-1970 September (Box 74, Folder 16)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. X, 1970 September-1971 March (Box 74, Folder 17)
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XI, Studies of members of a family, Book 2, 1969 May-1971 April (Box 74, Folder 18)
        Enzyme tests on named members of a family. Tests for chromosome abnormalities.
      - S.E. Malawista, General XI, Cyto[chalasin] Bs cont. (2nd set), 1970 April-1971 December (Box 75, Folder 1)
        Possibly Malawista misnumbered two notebooks XI.
      - S.E. Malawista, Vol. XII, Phage, Book 2, 1970 April-1971 April (Box 75, Folder 2)
      - J. W. Hollingswood, Tests on joint fluid of patients, 1966-1969 (Box 75, Folder 3)
        On Cover: "Day Book Patients." Patient names listed throughout. Restricted.
      - Log [of tests], 1968 January-1972 January (Box 75, Folder 4)
      - Course on Crystal Studies, Friday Harbor, Washington, 1968 June (Box 75, Folder 5)
      - S.E. Malawista, Friday Harbor, 1968 June (Box 75, Folder 6)
      - Sera stored, 1968 August-1977 October (Box 75, Folder 7)
        List of patient or donor names. Restricted.
      - R.H. Gifford, Lists of photographs, 1968-1974 (Box 75, Folder 8)